# **HUGH GREETHEAD**

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

(+61) 425 310 227 <u>hugh.greethead@gmail.com</u> Sydney, NSW

linkedin.com/in/hugh-greethead github.com/HughG-50

# **Education**

# Diploma of Information Technology

Coder Academy Web
Development Bootcamp 2020

# Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (Honours)

University of New South Wales 2013-17

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Ruby, Ruby on Rails JavaScript React, Express, Node.js PostgreSQL, MongoDB C

#### Other

Technical content writing Marketing and public relations Electronics Prototyping Control Systems Design

#### **PORTFOLIO**

hughgreethead.dev

## **PROFILE**

I am a self starter who loves embracing new challenges. I have project managed product teams, UX/UI research and business operations for a venture-backed fintech startup, as well as provided technical and strategic consulting for early stage startups.

My initial interest in programming started with my formal studies in Electrical Engineering and in my engineering work experience, where I contributed to the computer control systems design of the largest wheat mill in Australia. My interest in software development continued to grow while working with agile startup development teams to help deliver meaningful consumer and enterprise products.

During my time working in startups I self-taught web development, leading to the decision to fast-track my education through the Coder Academy bootcamp in 2020.

I am also an avid runner and enjoy investing.

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Technical Advisor**

Silver Ladder (Technical consulting agency for startups) May 2019 - Dec 2019, Singapore

- UX consulting focused on amplifying client value proposition through optimisation of user flows, screens, content, copy as well as UX research testing processes.
- Strategic consulting provided assisting startups to successfully pivot and rebrand for use cases that best suited their technology.
  - One company was assisted to pivot to a data services and governance provider, fundamental in a subsequent successful venture backed series A fundraise
- Front-end programming (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) for Silver Ladder website and on occasion for clients as needed.

## **Business Operations and Product**

Ren (Venture backed fintech startup) Sep 2017 - May 2019, Singapore

- Product lead for OTC trading chat application conducting product ideation, market research, project coordination and UI/UX design.
- Managed multiple product beta releases to 200+ beta users managing product feedback processes, technical support and refined UX A/B testing.
- Business development generated and maintained relationships with OTC trading desks, market makers and relevant industry partners grow trading flow and attract further investment opportunities.
- · Lead coordinator of a successful public crowdfunding campaign.

## Junior Electrical Engineer

Manildra Group (Agribusiness - milling and ethanol production) Nov 2016 - Mar 2017, Nowra

- Delivered control system designs (SCADA) for multi-million dollar flour milling plant upgrade project - process operators computer control interfaces/functional UIs
- Created and maintained extensive electrical engineering and technical documentation
- · Commissioning and verification of electrical sensors and components
- Performed power load analysis computations to calculate necessary equipment installations to relevant engineering standards

.